If you have good notes and you have very
very thoroughly mapped out a target and
you've captured all this information,
you can do this with little to no
overhead in your current bug bounty
flow.
>> Best part of backing when you can just,
you know, critical things, right?
Hello.
>> Yeah,
>> dude.
[Music]
>> All right, hackers. The ad read is going
to get a little technical today, so
buckle up for this, okay? I'm going to
tell you exactly how Threat Locker is
screwing hackers at every step along the
way with dynamic access controls,
preventing even port scans from
happening on Thread Locker networks. So,
uh, let's dive into it. There's three
primary ways that Thread Locker
implements this. I'm going to give you
guys two for this for this quick read.
Um and hopefully you'll be able to
understand how exactly they're
preventing hackers from doing port
scans. Um so first one is called local
challenge. This is on the common
scenario where a computer wants to
connect to a network resource and
they're on the same network. So what's
going to happen is over you know this
this threat locker handshake uh the
computer is going to send a request to
the server. the server is going to
respond with a challenge and then uh the
computer has to you know complete that
challenge and provide a response back to
the server before the SMB port is even
opened up to that specific computer
right so you can't do any port scanning
or anything like that because you're not
going through this handshake with the
computer um so that's that's one way the
next way is in like remote work
scenarios where your laptop is like you
know out on some Wi-Fi or whatever and
you still need to access network
resources um in this scenario the
computer is going to shoot an I, you
know, authenticated IP change up to the
threat locker cloud. Then when it
requests access to a specific server,
maybe it's trying to get in by like RDS
or whatever if it's if it's uh in a
remote work scenario, the RDS server,
you know, before it opens up that port
is going to query the allow list in the
thread locker cloud and say, "Hey, uh,
this IP is trying to connect. What
should I do with him?" Um, and then
threat locker cloud will give them a yes
or no on that and they'll open or close
the port based on that response. Okay.
So, with Threat Locker in place, really,
you can't even do port scans, guys. So,
tell you what, let's go back to the show
and hack something easier, and we'll let
Threat Locker do their thing. All right.
All right. Let's go. All right, hackers.
I've got an awesome article in the This
Week in Bug Bounty segment for you.
Okay. This is Yes, We Hacks: Minefield
Between Syntaxes: Exploiting Syntax
Confusions in the Wild. And I learned so
much from this just reading over this
article. Okay, so typically in this
segment I'm just going to give you
articles to go read and give you a
summary of them. This time we're
actually going to dive in a little bit.
Okay, so let's check this out. This
article is focused on syntax confusion,
which is essentially just weird ways to
um represent syntax in various contexts
and the research here is lovely. Okay,
the first one blew my freaking mind.
Look at this. Okay, what is this code?
How does this work? Okay, apparently
there are these things called triraphphs
and diagraphs in C's or in C which is um
character sequences such as question
mark question mark equal sign or um
percent sign colon or uh less than
percent sign and these just are
converted by the compiler into different
characters on the fly. So this C code
right here, which uh I I'm sorry for
those of you listening, but this C code
here that just has no curly brackets at
all and just uses less than sign percent
sign, compiles totally fine and runs.
Crazy. Absolutely crazy. So look up C
diagraphs and triraphphs. Um less than
percent sign is equal to the left curly
bracket or the open curly bracket. It's
like how does this even exist? These are
the things that hackers need to know so
that we can do cool syntax bypasses.
Okay, so that was the first one.
Um, the next one was uh parsing on
specific ports, right? Like you can uh
pad your zeros uh your port number with
zeros in a URL, right? So 0000443,
right? Same thing as 443. Um, oh, this
one was really interesting. Apparently
in Python, you can reference specific
characters, Unicode characters using
their back slash capital N syntax. So
back slash capital N Greek capital
letter delta in all caps. It will give
you the actual character point for that.
Like what is this back slash capital N
with curly brackets syntax in in Python
and Pearl is super weird. Um and
apparently there's a back slashp curly
brackets um syntax as well that is just
whack. Um, oh, okay. And then check this
one out, guys. In in um you guys have
seen content disposition all the time in
your u multiart form um HTTP request,
right? Apparently, there's another
format for this, right? Where it's not
just file name equals my file.txt. You
could do file name equals uh asterisk
equals and then specify like a character
set like UTF8 and then provide that um
file name. Okay, so now we can smuggle
in unic code characters into our file
names in content disposition uh on
multiart form HTTP requests. Okay, which
is going to be awesome for unicorn
normalization. Um
so good. Okay, so anyway, this article
by Yes, we hack is phenomenal. It's
chalk full of these sort of syntax
confusions and real life uh bug bounty
finds, right? like um that he does a a
full read SSRF
uh and a cache poisoning bug. So go
ahead and check out this write up. We'll
link it in the description. The
minefield between syntax is exploiting
the syntax confusions in the wild and
check out those like C triraphphs and
diagramraphs and the back/ capital N
syntax to access unicode code points in
Python and Pearl. All right, uh let's
get to the main content. I think Brandon
is doing an episode today by himself,
which is awesome. He's going to rock it.
Um, play pay play pay close attention to
this, okay? Because taking notes in Bug
Bounty is extremely extremely extremely
important. Um, and Brandon is the go-to
hacker in my opinion that does this
extremely well. So, lots of good content
here. Enjoy y'all.
>> Hello everyone. It's Brandon Brett me.
We've got a bit of a different episode
uh today for you. It's going to be
shorter as it's a solo episode, but it
covers one of the topics I've personally
had a lot of questions on and has led to
a lot of success for me personally as a
bug hunter, and that's how to have
long-term success on a target and my
note-taking methodology for that. Now,
full transparency, this is also coming
from a hunter who is most definitely not
a recon guy. Um, that's not me. It never
has been. So long-term success on the
target really boils down to my note
takingaking, my JavaScript monitoring,
my general target monitoring outside of
JavaScript monitoring and also uh
collabing. We'll start off with the
notes as it feeds into everything else I
do on my approach. Um but hopefully it
makes sense. So for the audio listeners,
I will be sharing my screen, but I'll do
my absolute best to talk through it as
well.
Okay,
so my notes essentially starts off with
a default template every time. I
personally use notion. I'm pretty much
embedded into notion. Um, but you can
use whatever you like as long as you
capture all this information. I don't
really think it matters too much. So my
default template first consists of the
target, the target's text stack, and
what I'm looking at here is really the
framework and the languages in use, any
third party components in use, whether
that's certain libraries for billing,
JavaScript, widgets, things like that.
Um, if it has any reliance on other
applications, what database it uses and
all those kinds of things. That's the
first part of the notes and what opens
up the target. Then after that, uh, the
brainstorming risks section. Now, this
is essentially where I threat model. And
this is also the area where you're going
to want to put down every single attack
vector you can possibly think of and
everything that you've tried. Um, so for
example, I've got a little note here for
myself to threat model and highlight
high-risk areas to target first and then
walk through that. And how I actually
take these notes is I have the endpoint
or the functionality. I have a bullet
point for the information um that I
captured from that and I also have a
little tick box for the actual check
that I want to do. Now the idea here is
that you put down all your checks but
I'll come back onto this later on. Now I
also have a high signal area and this is
an area where if you're hunting for a
long time on the target and you've
identified a really high signal search
whether that be a Google dork um a very
high signal GP for example in JavaScript
files or just kind of how they identify
their roots whether that be API client
side whatever it might be that goes down
in my high signal section and what that
allows me to do is whenever I'm looking
for something quick um I can just
quickly come back to here and and search
for that and see it straight away on the
target. The other thing as well, I have
an error oracle section and I don't
really hear too much talk about this
although I see a lot of hunters
inadvertingly doing this and tracking
them. And an error oracle is essentially
a a part of the application or an
endpoint that you can use to
intentionally force an error to disclose
information about the target, the
system, the application, the process,
whatever you're looking at. So say for
example you have identified that there's
a very very sketchy endpoint that when
you instead of putting in I don't know a
URL starting with HTTP you put in a URL
starting with or a URI starting with FTP
and it causes it to fall over. It gives
you the internal host in use. It
discloses some ports maybe even some
authentication headers. Put that down in
your error oracle. The reason I have a
section for error oracles is because
there has been more times than I can
count where I have disclosed a bunch of
information whether that's through a
verbose error um whether that's through
just general fuzzing whatever it might
be and it hasn't ever been useful to me
at that time it's good information to
have but it wasn't useful to me I
couldn't exploit it put that down in
your
section in your notes and I can pretty
much guarantee you if you hunt on the
target for a long time that will come in
useful. One example of this is I was in
a live event in I think it was in April
and I had an error Oracle where I could
disclose a ton of information about an
internal service in use including
internal host names, authentication
headers, ports, everything. a lot of
information. I noted it down wasn't
useful maybe last month or the month
before that information actually came in
useful when I was building out an attack
chain on a similar but different area of
the target. So definitely note those
down. They are invaluable especially
when you're hunting longterm on a
target. And then the last part is attack
paths and gadgets. And this sort of
feeds into the other two, but if I'm
building out an attack path, um, or I
have a bunch of gadgets, whether that be
client side path traversal, weapon
redirect, um, a quirk in there, or flow,
things like that, I note them all down
here. And even if it's semi-built out
attack chains, they still go down. They
still come in useful. And I also have a
tracker at the bottom. Um, and if I am
actively working on multiple um, attack
chains or multiple bugs which are
convoluted and I can't get done in one
session, they'll go down into my tracker
at the bottom. So, I'll show you what
this looks like on an old target. And
this is an older version from a target
maybe last year that I was looking at.
And I've noted everything down here. So
first of all it starts off with all of
the scope and credentials for example.
Um then we've got the behavior. Now
this is very very nice information to
capture. If you look at a target for a
couple of months don't look at it and
then come back to it. This is sort of
information that will let you look at
your notes and hit the ground running.
So I've got release notes for the
target. I've got support documentation
for the target. I've got documentation
on their access controls if they have
weekly demos and webinars on new
functionality. Uh documentation on their
user and off matrix. All of that is
captured so I can come back, save it,
refer to it at a later date. Also have
the behavior of what the target does. Um
information on the text stack, the user
levels, framework and language. Um
didn't fill out the third party
components here for whatever reason.
Now, this here is for me what makes me
effective, I think, as a hunter because
I threat model and I threat model a lot
on targets and every single thing I can
think of, whether that's um related to,
I don't know, basic idle testing, XSS,
more exotic authentication bugs, um
everything, and I mean everything goes
down in here. So for example, the first
point here is I've got cookie signed
using Rails but can be removed um with a
screenshot as well which I've toggled so
you can't see it. Um and all all of
these checks so email functionality
export import account functionality and
the checks I've done I've ticked off for
example here error cause 500 when
important HTML file. Now, I'm showing
you an adapted version obviously because
I can't disclose too much information,
but this allows me to list all my attack
vectors. And for everyone watching this,
it's just genuinely and I'm like massive
massive page of all of these different
attack vectors, all of my different
notes, what worked, what didn't work. um
so I can keep track of the target and
thoroughly assess each piece of
functionality and be sure that I have
thoroughly assessed it. Now the idea
here is that these notes are a living
breathing document. You don't ever
really want to complete them. You want
to list down as many attack vectors as
you can possibly find. Whether that's
from new research you've had, whether
that is if the targets release new
functionality,
whether whatever it might be, this is a
living breathing document that you
always append to and always keep notes
of. Now the good thing is when you get
to a certain threshold in your notes and
you have a lot of information about the
target, this enables you to really
effectively collab with someone. And
what I mean by this is if you feel like
you have absolutely
kicked the living daylights out of a
target and you feel like that you can't
push it any further, at least for now
until a couple of months time, you can
pass these notes to another hacker and
they can just hit the ground running,
see what worked, get some immediate
feedback, get some immediate gadgets,
get a feel for the target within, I
don't know how long would this take to
read, maybe 10 minutes to get to
thoroughly read them and they can just
go and get hunting. Now, there isn't a
recent example I can think of this and I
hope they don't mind me shouting them
out, but Green Jam and JRock have been
collabing a lot and sharing notes on a
target that they both look at pretty
heavily and they have absolutely cleaned
the floor just by sharing notes and
sharing gadgets on things that they both
looked at but maybe couldn't exploit at
the time and it's been a bit of a blood
bath. So very very useful. Um which is
why it's one of my big things on a
long-term target. Now the other thing is
as well JavaScript monitoring. Um I'm
not going to get into the weeds of what
tools to use, what frameworks to use and
things like that. I'm just going to tell
you some very high signal things I
monitor for which does let you identify
if there's been a new change on the
target. And you obviously want to be the
first one to look at that. So, first of
all, you want to and let me just go back
for a second. If you have good notes and
you have very very thoroughly mapped out
a target and you've captured all this
information,
you can do this with little to no
overhead in your current bug bounty
flow. Say for example, you've mapped out
exactly how their endpoints, their
roots, their permission sets are mapped
out in JavaScript and you have that in
your high signal search area of your
notes. You can do all this very quickly.
It would just be a case of spinning up a
server, identifying, creating a few
reixes maybe, and setting up that
monitoring. You'll be completely good to
go, which is why I'm so keen on having
really good nodes. But anyway, the
things I look for are request handlers,
endpoint declarations, user permissions,
user flags, and content types. Now, I
have this as a template to remind myself
of things to look for because I can fall
into a bit of a bit of a hole when I'm
hunting and just forget to do certain
things. So, having my notes is very
essential. And if you've collabed with
me or worked with me, like Justin will
know this. If I need to do something and
it isn't written down, I chances are I'm
never ever going to do it. So anyway,
I have things like uh or off and session
flows which I look at which is uses of
things like local storage, session
storage, post message. Um
I monitor new endpoints associated with
the password reset and password recovery
flows if there are one. Another big one
as well is privilege and feature
controls. So
you might look at a and every target is
obviously going to be different but
there might be cases where you will see
a lot of strings in JavaScript to show
you client side roots and different
permissions with things like is staff is
internal entitlements scopes is admin um
is user is all these different sort of
roles. If you can identify exactly how
these are defined throughout an app and
monitor them, you can pretty much be
sure that if you get a new hit on one of
these, there's going to be a new user
role or new functionality coming out
which probably hasn't been looked at if
you're quick enough. And that's going to
be very high signal for you. And I've
had a lot of success personally
identifying these different roles and
making sure I'm monitoring for them.
Another thing as well is feature flags.
Justin talks a lot about this in his um
in some of his previous talks around
response
like rewriting and things like that. If
you can identify new feature flags for
AB testing again you can just pretty
much unlock most times new functionality
and new attack surface. Um obviously
you've got your endpoint discovery as
well. you want to look at how these are
identified and one thing here is I've
noticed with a lot of standard
monitoring I've looked at there's a lot
of focus around naturally HTTP HTTPS
URLs but you also have websockets and
that's very target specific so if you
can set up monitoring for that as well
that could be very high signal GraphQL
you've got method and verbs um you also
have
query um parameters and depending on how
they're defined on the target, you'll
get different return on investment
there. Now, other things I have more
recently started monitoring for as well,
which I touched upon earlier is client
side syncs. Um before my monitoring was
heavily focused around endpoints and
roles and um feature flags and things
like that, but that can also be quite
high signal. If you're monitoring
JavaScript um and you've set it up, you
might as well do the extra extra
overhead as well to to look at the other
things.
Um what else have we got? And I've just
got a few other high signal things I'd
try to look for. File and content
handling, service workers,
um framework specific hotspots. This is
a good one. If you have like an XJS
target for example or if you're they're
using GraphQL, there's going to be
patterns you can lock into on those
targets which will be very high signal
and allow you to harvest things a lot
more easier.
Um, and yeah, I've given myself some
handy reject snippets and examples just
to remind myself and quickly set up
JavaScript monitoring. The whole point
of this and the whole point of the notes
is to have very high signal, very
frictionless things that you can do to
adds to your hunting uh processes which
give you a pretty much immediate or
close to immediate ROI which is as less
overhead as possible to to implement. So
that's kind of what it looks like. And
the important thing to note here as
well, let's just go into here. Okay,
this is an example of a of another
application that I set up to demo. If
you have a target which for example is
more of an ecosystem than a single app
and there's multiple APIs or if it's a
star. Scope for example, I just
personally create another page in here
and I start the process all over again.
uh I create a page per application or
page per API and go through that process
again. You start off with your endpoint
or your functionality. You have your
bullet point to capture the information
on that what it does. Then you have your
check on the actual check to perform. So
test for the idle in the idle parameter.
I wish it has an idle parameter in the
ID parameter
as it's reflected.
And then once you complete this check,
you go back up here and then you add
your feedback from that check and say
it's not possible escaped
properly in ID parameter. And yeah,
that's sort of how I map that out in my
flow. As I said,
the idea here is that you capture all
this information and you want to go with
the mindset of, okay, this is for
long-term success where you want to
capture the high signal things, which
might not be useful in that current
moment you're hunting, but later on down
the line, it most definitely is. And for
me, the the thing when this really
clicked and made sense was my first
month in hunting. I started in January
this year full-time
and obviously it's quite daunting when
you start hunting. The very first thing
I done I went through all my notes for
all my regular targets about four or
five targets I regularly look at and my
entire first month and I'm being 100%
serious here was pretty much bred from
my notes and things that I noted down
wasn't useful to me at the time. I come
back with a fresh set of eyes or there's
been new functionality or if I'd found
new gadgets on that target later on down
the line which I had also noted down and
I could basically just chain them
together, carry on hunting and that was
pretty much my first month. I done that.
I also went through my old bug reports
and bypass them. So perhaps you don't
have notes right now. Um I will be
releasing my templates that I use. These
are my stripped down ones for people to
use and apply universally across targets
so they can cater towards whatever
they're looking at. I use notion.
They'll probably be releasing the hacker
notes. And if you're just getting
started, my flow on how I do this
personally, I'll sit down on the target
for a couple of hours. I'll go through
I'll map out the application take my
initial notes from there and then say
every I don't know at the end of every
day after that point I'll note down my
attack vectors check my proxy log check
my burp history history check my Kaido
history go through all that and note
down the things that did work didn't
work my error oracles my high signal
searches all the gadgets I found from
that day on now if you want a bit of a
cheat code to get started if you don't
do this already start by going through
your old reports on a target noting down
everything that you did find bugs in,
how you found them, the end points
they're found in, the parameters they're
found in, the bug type, if there were
any error of course identified in that,
and start off with that. You might be
able to start bypassing all fixes and
things. So, what this does, it might not
be the sexiest method to get started off
in, but it does definitely allow you to
capture a lot of information to come
back to that information at a later date
and hit a target hard. Now, as I said
earlier, if you can capture all that and
give this to another hunter, and let's
say, for example, you are looking to
collab and you're not sure who to collab
with, contact one of the top 20, top 15,
top 10 hunters on the program you're
looking at. ask if they want to collab,
build that trust, and maybe start
sharing your notes. And I can guarantee
that if you've captured them in this
level, in this format, you will be able
to start sharing notes, collabing, and
getting more information. So, I hope you
find it useful. The templates on all of
this my on my notes on basic JavaScript
monitoring the things I captured exactly
what you're looking at here will be cap
um will be shared with you on I'm
guessing it's going to be the hacker
notes and you can clone this in notion.
If you don't use notion just use a
similar layout to whatever your favorite
note takingaking is and it it will work.
I hope you find it useful. I've had a
lot of questions on this. I haven't
really shown it in this much depth
before and again it's not the sexiest
but it will most definitely allow you to
capture a lot of information which will
lead to longerterm success on a target
and allow you to essentially get free
bugs when you have enough information
captured and you revisit a target at a
later date. It's worked for me. I've
shown a few hunters it. I've had good
feedback overall on it. I've given some
hunters I've collabed with my notes and
it's allowed them to hit the ground
running and start hunting very quickly.
So, hope you find it useful. As I said,
bit of a different episode today. Bit of
a shorter episode as well, but this
might be useful to some of you. So, let
me know what you think. I'll be sharing
them. And yeah, thank you everyone.
>> And that's a wrap on this episode of
Critical Thinking. Thanks so much for
watching to the end, y'all. If you want
more critical thinking content, uh, or
if you want to support the show, head
over to ctbb.show/isord.
You can hop in the community. There's
lots of great highlevel hacking
discussion happening there on top of
master classes, hackalongs, exclusive
content, and a full-time hunters guild
if you're a full-time hunter. It's a
great time. Trust me. All right, I'll
see you there.